Finding Aid for Stephen M. Ross School of Business (University of Michigan) records, 1916-2017
Bentley Historical Library
- Russell A. Stevenson and Predecessors Series, 1916-1960
  - Dean's Administrative Records, 1916-1960
    - Alphabetical, 1916-1959; 1924-1944
      - Faculty and Staff
        - Outside Employment Regulations, 1939 (Box 4)
        - Personnel File, A-Z, 1924-1942; 30 folders (Box 5)
        - Retirement Allowance, 1929 (Box 5)
        - Rules, 1925-1939 (Box 5)
      - Federal Government
        - Business Research, 1945-1946; 2 folders (Box 5)
        - Committee on Occupational Deferment, 1943-1945 (Box 5)
        - G.I. Bill, 1944-1946; 8 folders (Box 5)
        - Mead Bill, 1943-1944; 2 folders (Box 6)
        - Smaller War Plants Corporation, 1944-1945 (Box 6)
        - Training Programs, 1941-1945; 7 folders (Box 6)
        - Veterans, 1944-1946; 3 folders (Box 6)
      - Grades and Statistics, 1925-1957 (Box 6)
      - Graduate Students
        - Graduate School, 1924-1941 (Box 6)
        - Ph.D Examination Questions, 1929-1939 (Box 6)
      - Honors Convocation, 1927-1941 (Box 6)
      - Michigan Business Review, 1949-1955; 3 folders (Box 6)
      - Michigan State Planning Commission, 1944-1946
        - General, 3 folders (Box 6)
        - Regional Meetings, 10 folders (Box 6)
      - Placement, 1929-1941; 8 folders (Box 6)
      - Placement, 1940-1944; 6 folders (Box 7)
      - Psychological Tests, 1931-1941 (Box 7)
      - Radio Programs, 1932-1936 (Box 7)
      - Scholarships and Fellowships
        - Alumni Club of Pittsburgh, 1939-1949 (Box 7)
        - American Bankers Association, 1929-1941 (Box 7)
        - Ann Arbor Board of Realtors, 1946-1950 (Box 7)
        - Ann Arbor Federal Savings and Loan, 1947-1950 (Box 7)
        - Arthur Anderson, 1940-1941 (Box 7)
        - Earhart, 1932-1935 (Box 7)
        - Edwin F. Gay Awards, 1949 (Box 7)
        - General University
          - 1937-1938 (Box 7)
          - 1946-1950 (Box 7)
          - 1950-1951 (Box 7)
        - Junior Executives Club (Box 7)
        - Michigan College Scholarships, 1935-1951; 8 folders (Box 7)
        - Michigan Real Estate Association, 1946-1950 (Box 7)
        - Morse Memorial Foundation, 1950-1951 (Box 7)
        - National Institute for Commerce and Trade Organizations, 1948-1950 (Box 7)
        - Proposals, 1944-1954 (Box 7)
        - Real Estate, 1927-1941; 2 folders (Box 7)
        - Summer Accounting, 1939-1941 (Box 7)
        - Tachna, Lionel J., 1932-1941 (Box 7)
        - University Scholarships, 1932-1941 (Box 7)
      - Students
        - Activities
          - Business Administration Club, 1925-1928 (Box 7)
          - Business Administration Council, 1948-1960; 2 folders (Box 7)
          - Capitalists Ball, 1938-1941 (Box 7)
          - Fraternities and Sororities, 1927-1958; 8 folders (Box 7)
        - Admissions Requirements, 1931-1932 (Box 7)
        - Comparison of University of Michigan students with Transfer Students from Michigan Colleges, 1931-1933 (Box 7)
        - Comparison of University of Michigan Students with non-Michigan Students (Enrollment), 1935 (Box 7)
        - Grades
          - General, 1931-1937 (Box 7)
          - Graphs, 1924-1940 (Box 7)
          - Study, 1939 (Box 7)
        - Graduates, Study of those in Michigan, 1940 (Box 7)
        - Opinion Survey, undated (Box 7)
        - Statistics, 1924-1947; 29 folders (Box 8)
        - Time Spent on Course Preparation, 1934-1935 (Box 8)
    - Chronological
      - 1944-1948
        - A General (Box 8)
        - Alexander Hamilton Institute (Box 8)
        - American Accounting Association (Box 8)
        - American Arbitration Association, 2 folders (Box 8)
        - American Association of Collegiate Schools of Business, 7 folders (Box 8)
        - American Council on Education (Box 8)
        - American Economics Association, 2 folders (Box 8)
        - American Institute of Accountants (Box 9)
        - American Institute of Real Estate Appraisers (Box 9)
        - Apprenticeship Training (Box 9)
        - B General (Box 9)
        - Banking School (Box 9)
        - Beta Gamma Sigma (Box 9)
        - Brookings Institution
          - General Motors Study, 2 folders (Box 9)
          - Stevenson's Notes re GM Study (Box 9)
        - C General (Box 9)
        - Cargill, Inc (Box 9)
        - Chrysler Corporation (Box 9)
        - Committee for Economic Development (Box 9)
        - Controllers Institute of America (Box 9)
        - Cooperative Counselor Training Program (Box 9)
        - D General (Box 9)
        - Delta Pi Epsilon (Box 9)
        - Delta Sigma Pi (Box 9)
        - Detroit Board of Commerce (Box 9)
        - Detroit Edison Company, 2 folders (Box 9)
        - Detroit Real Estate Board (Box 9)
        - Dow Memorial (Box 9)
        - E General (Box 9)
        - Economic Club of Detroit, 2 folders (Box 9)
        - F General (Box 9)
        - Federal Reserve Bank (Box 9)
        - Ford Motor Company (Box 9)
        - G General (Box 9)
        - General Mills, 2 folders (Box 9)
        - Gerber's Baby Foods (Box 9)
        - H General (Box 9)
        - I General (Box 9)
        - Industrial Relations (Box 9)
        - J General (Box 9)
        - K General (Box 9)
        - L General (Box 9)
        - Labor Unions (Box 9)
        - M General (Box 9)
        - Manuel, Ralph W (Box 10)
        - Michigan, State of (Box 10)
        - Michigan Association of Certified Public Accountants (Box 10)
        - Michigan, Department of Economic Development (Box 10)
        - Michigan Real Estate Association (Box 10)
        - Michigan State College (Box 10)
        - Midwest Economics Association (Box 10)
        - Minnesota, University of, 2 folders (Box 10)
        - Mises, Ludwig von (Box 10)
        - N General (Box 10)
        - Nash-Kelvinator Corp. (H.D. Wehrly) (Box 10)
        - National Conference of State University Schools of Business (Box 10)
        - National Student Association (Box 10)
        - New York State-Certified Public Accountants (Box 10)
        - O General (Box 10)
        - Ohio State University-75th Anniversary (Box 10)
        - Oldsmobile (Box 10)
        - P General (Box 10)
        - Q General (Box 10)
        - R General (Box 10)
        - Regents (Box 10)
        - Reniger Construction Company, Meeting on Apprenticeship Program (Box 10)
        - Rotary Club (Box 10)
        - S General (Box 10)
        - Stevenson, R.A., 2 folders (Box 10)
        - Survey Research Center Dinner, October 23, 1947 (Box 10)
        - T General (Box 10)
        - Tax Amendment (Box 10)
        - Twin Cities Plan-Postwar Taxes (Box 10)
        - U General (Box 10)
        - United States
          - Department of Commerce (Box 10)
          - Employment Service (Box 10)
        - Upgreen, Arthur R (Box 10)
        - V General (Box 10)
        - W General (Box 10)
        - XYZ General (Box 10)
      - 1949-1951
        - A General (Box 11)
        - Adams, J.P., Certificate (1919) and Gift Fund (Box 11)
        - American Accounting Association (Box 11)
        - American Arbitration Association (Box 11)
        - American Association of Collegiate Schools of Business, 9 folders (Box 11)
        - American Council on Education, 4 folders (Box 11)
        - American Economic Association (Box 11)
        - American Institute of Accountants (Box 11)
        - Ann Arbor Bank (Box 11)
        - B General (Box 11)
        - Beta Gamma Sigma (Box 11)
        - Book Industry Study (Box 11)
        - Brookings Institution, 13 folders (Box 11)
        - C General (Box 11)
        - Campbell, Harvey (Box 11)
        - Committee for Economic Development (Box 11)
        - Controllers Institute of America (Box 11)
        - D General (Box 12)
        - Delta Pi Epsilon (Box 12)
        - Delta Sigma Pi (Box 12)
        - Detroit Board of Commerce (Box 12)
        - Detroit Edison Company (Box 12)
        - Detroit Institute of Technology (Box 12)
        - Detroit Sales Executives Club (Box 12)
        - Detroit Trust Company (Box 12)
        - Dodge, Joseph M (Box 12)
        - E General (Box 12)
        - Earhart Unemployment Compensation Case Studies (Box 12)
        - Economic Club of Detroit, 4 folders (Box 12)
        - Economic Club of Detroit, 2 folders (Box 12)
        - Economy Housing Program (Box 12)
        - F General (Box 12)
        - Ford Foundation (Box 12)
        - G General (Box 12)
        - General Mills, Inc (Box 12)
        - General Motors Corporation (Box 12)
        - Grand Rapids-contacts to be made (Box 12)
        - H General (Box 12)
        - I General (Box 12)
        - Illinois, University of (Box 12)
        - J General (Box 12)
        - K General (Box 12)
        - King, Wilfred T.C (Box 12)
        - L General (Box 12)
        - Loyola University (Box 12)
        - M General (Box 12)
        - McCormick Historical Association (Box 12)
        - Merrill Foundation (Box 12)
        - Michigan, State of (Box 12)
        - Michigan Academy of Science, Arts and Letters (Box 12)
        - Michigan College Association (Box 12)
        - Michigan, Colleges (Box 12)
        - Michigan Council on Economic Development (Box 12)
        - Michigan, Department of Economic Development (Box 12)
        - Michigan Joint Legislative Committee (Box 13)
        - Michigan Real Estate Association (Box 13)
        - Michigan Retailers Association (Box 13)
        - Michigan State College, 2 folders (Box 13)
        - Michigan Tradesman (Box 13)
        - Minnesota Economics Club (Box 13)
        - Minnesota, University of, 2 folders (Box 13)
        - N General (Box 13)
        - National Association of Manufacturers (Box 13)
        - National Bureau of Economic Research (Box 13)
        - National Management Council (Box 13)
        - O General (Box 13)
        - P General (Box 13)
        - Palmer, Walter S. (Box 13)
        - Perrin, Oliver W. (Box 13)
        - Public Relations (Box 13)
        - R General (Box 13)
        - Regents (Box 13)
        - Rotary Club (Box 13)
        - S General (Box 13)
        - Seeley Foundation (Box 13)
        - T General (Box 13)
        - U General (Box 13)
        - United States
          - Air Force, Institute of Technology (Box 13)
          - Department of Commerce (Box 13)
        - V General (Box 13)
        - W General (Box 13)
        - Wayne University (Box 13)
        - XYZ General (Box 13)
      - 1951-1953
        - A General (Box 13)
        - Alexander Hamilton Institute (Box 13)
        - American Association of Collegiate Schools of Business, 6 folders (Box 13)
        - American Council on Education (Box 13)
        - Ann Arbor Bank (Box 13)
        - Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce (Box 13)
        - B General (Box 13)
        - Beta Gamma Sigma (Box 13)
        - Boffo, Louis S (Box 13)
        - Builders' and Trader's Exchange (Box 13)
        - C General (Box 13)
        - Chrysler Corporation (Box 13)
        - Commission on Human Resources-Testing Program (Box 13)
        - Committee for Economic Development, 2 folders (Box 13)
        - Commission on University Education in Hospital Administration (Box 13)
        - D General (Box 13)
        - Delta Pi Epsilon (Box 13)
        - Detroit Board of Commerce (Box 13)
        - Detroit Edison Company (Box 13)
        - Detroit Institute of Technology (Box 13)
        - Discrimination, Midwest Regional Committee on ... in Higher Education (Box 13)
        - E General (Box 14)
        - Economic Club of Detroit, 5 folders (Box 14)
        - Educational Testing Service (Box 14)
        - F General (Box 14)
        - G General (Box 14)
        - General Motors Corporation (Box 14)
        - H General (Box 14)
        - I General (Box 14)
        - Institute for Economic Education (Box 14)
        - J General (Box 14)
        - K General (Box 14)
        - L General (Box 14)
        - M General (Box 14)
        - Michigan, State of (Box 14)
        - Michigan Bell Telephone Company (Box 14)
        - Michigan, Colleges (Box 14)
        - Michigan Council on Economic Education (Box 14)
        - Michigan, Department of Economic Development (Box 14)
        - Michigan Labor Mediation Board (Box 14)
        - Michigan State College (Box 14)
        - Minnesota, University of (Box 14)
        - N General (Box 14)
        - National Association of Bank Auditors (Box 14)
        - National Management Council, 2 folders (Box 14)
        - O General (Box 14)
        - P General (Box 14)
        - Philippines, University of (Box 14)
        - R General (Box 14)
        - Regents (Box 14)
        - Riley Stoker Corporation (Box 14)
        - Rotary Club (Box 14)
        - S General (Box 14)
        - Seeley Foundation (Box 14)
        - Small Industries Council of Michigan (Box 14)
        - Stevenson, R.A., personal (Box 14)
        - T General (Box 14)
        - U-V General (Box 14)
        - United States Air Force Armament Study (Box 14)
        - W General (Box 14)
        - Wayne University (Box 14)
        - Woodworth, George (Box 14)
        - Wright-Patterson Air Force Base Management Course (Box 14)
        - XYZ General (Box 14)
      - 1954-July 1956
        - A General (Box 15)
        - Airey, John (Box 15)
        - American Association of Collegiate Schools of Business, 10 folders (Box 15)
        - American Council on Education, 2 folders (Box 15)
        - American Enterprise Association Advisory Board (Box 15)
        - American Trade Association Executives. Mackinac Island (Box 15)
        - Ann Arbor Bank (Box 15)
        - Ann Arbor Business Men (Box 15)
        - B General (Box 15)
        - Brookings Institution (Box 15)
        - C General (Box 15)
        - Campbell-Ewald Project (Box 15)
        - Chronowski, Alois J. (Box 15)
        - Chrysler Corporation (Box 15)
        - Collegiate Associates for Market Measurement (Box 15)
        - Committee for Economic Development (Box 15)
        - Conference of Bank Correspondents (Box 15)
        - Consumers Power Company, Jackson, Michigan (Box 15)
        - Council for International Progress in Management (Box 15)
        - D General (Box 15)
        - Delta Sigma Pi, 2 folders (Box 15)
        - Detroit Board of Commerce (Box 15)
        - Detroit Institute of Technology (Box 15)
        - Detroit Sales Executives Club (Box 15)
        - E General (Box 15)
        - Economic Club of Detroit (Box 15)
        - Educational Testing Service, 3 folders (Box 15)
        - European Trip (Box 15)
        - F General (Box 15)
        - Ford Foundation Fellowships (Box 16)
        - Ford Motor Company (Box 16)
        - Foundation for Research in Human Behavior (Box 16)
        - G General (Box 16)
        - H General (Box 16)
        - Harvard University (Box 16)
        - Hawaii, January 16-26, 1955 (Box 16)
        - I-J General (Box 16)
        - K General (Box 16)
        - Kunstadter, Sigmund W. (Box 16)
        - L General (Box 16)
        - Life Insurance Agency Management Association, March 27-29, 1955 (Box 16)
        - M General (Box 16)
        - Michigan, State of (Box 16)
        - Michigan Consumer Finance Association (Box 16)
        - Michigan Council on Economic Education (Box 16)
        - Michigan, Department of Economic Development (Box 16)
        - Michigan Economic Development Commission (Box 16)
        - Michigan State College (Box 16)
        - Michigan Tax Proposal (Box 16)
        - Minnesota, University of (Box 16)
        - Mortgage Bankers Association (Box 16)
        - N General (Box 16)
        - National Association of Manufacturers (Box 16)
        - National Association of Real Estate Boards (Box 16)
        - National Bureau of Economic Research (Box 16)
        - National Consumer Finance Association, Chapel Hill, April 3-5, 1955 (Box 16)
        - National Planning Association (Box 16)
        - Newcomen Society (Box 16)
        - O General (Box 16)
        - P General (Box 16)
        - Pennsylvania Salt Co., Wyandotte, 2 folders (Box 16)
        - Provident Mutual Life Insurance Co (Box 16)
        - Q-R General (Box 16)
        - Regents (Box 16)
        - Robert G. Rodkey Graduate Fellowship and Scholarship Fund in Banking (Box 16)
        - Rosenthal Foundation (Box 16)
        - S General (Box 16)
        - Scott Paper Co (Box 16)
        - Small Business Administration (Box 16)
        - Sumner, Charles E., Jr. (Columbia University) (Box 16)
        - T General (Box 16)
        - Tax Executives Institute, 2 folders (Box 16)
        - U-V General (Box 16)
        - W General (Box 16)
        - Wisconsin, University of, Elwell Dinner, April 25, 1955 (Box 16)
        - XYZ General (Box 16)
      - 1956-1959
        - A General (Box 17)
        - A.C. Spark Plug (Box 17)
        - Acme Quality Paints (Box 17)
        - Alumni Survey (Box 17)
        - American Association of Collegiate Schools of Business, 6 folders (Box 17)
        - American Council on Education (Box 17)
        - American Economic Association, December 27-28, 1958 (Box 17)
        - Ann Arbor Bank (Box 17)
        - Ann Arbor Business Men-Faculty Group (Box 17)
        - Ann Arbor, City of, Subcommittee on Finance (Box 17)
        - B General (Box 17)
        - Buffalo, University of Michigan Club of (Box 17)
        - C General (Box 17)
        - Carnegie Institute of Technology, Ford Foundation Seminar (Box 17)
        - Carnegie Survey (Box 17)
        - Chana Cariola, Dr. Julio (Box 17)
        - Chicago, University of (Box 17)
        - Christian Science Monitor, Article on the School of Business (Box 17)
        - Council for International Progress in Management (Box 17)
        - Counseling Survey (Box 17)
        - D General (Box 17)
        - Dearborn Center, University of Michigan, 3 folders (Box 17)
        - Detroit Edison Company (Box 17)
        - Detroit Free Press (Box 17)
        - Detroit Sales Executive Club (Box 17)
        - E General (Box 17)
        - Economic Club of Detroit (Box 17)
        - Educational Testing Service (Box 17)
        - European Economic Cooperation, Organization for (Box 17)
        - F General (Box 17)
        - Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago (Box 17)
        - Ford Foundation (Box 17)
        - Foundation for Research on Human Behavior (Box 17)
        - G General (Box 17)
        - General Motors Corporation (Box 17)
        - Great Lakes Industrial Development Council (Box 17)
        - H General (Box 17)
        - Hale, Clayton G (Box 17)
        - Harvard University (Box 17)
        - I General (Box 18)
        - J General (Box 18)
        - K General (Box 18)
        - L General (Box 18)
        - M General (Box 18)
        - Michigan, State of (Box 18)
        - Michigan Colleges (Box 18)
        - Michigan Commission on College Accreditation (Box 18)
        - Michigan Council on Economic Education, 5 folders (Box 18)
        - Michigan, Department of Economic Development, 2 folders (Box 18)
        - Michigan Economic Development Commission, 3 folders (Box 18)
        - Michigan Legislative Study Committee on Higher Education (Box 18)
        - Michigan State University (Box 18)
        - Minnesota, University of (Box 18)
        - N General (Box 18)
        - National Academy of Contractors and Engineers, Inc (Box 18)
        - National Association of Manufacturers (Box 18)
        - National Bureau of Economic Research (Box 18)
        - National Consumer Credit Conference (Box 18)
        - National Planning Association (Box 18)
        - Newsletter (Monroe Street Journal) (Box 18)
        - Newspaper Research Project (Box 18)
        - O General (Box 18)
        - P General (Box 18)
        - Pegrum, Dudley (Box 18)
        - Pew Foundation (Box 18)
        - Power, Eugene B (Box 18)
        - R General (Box 18)
        - Roosevelt University, December 1, 1958 (Box 18)
        - Rotary (Box 18)
        - S General (Box 18)
        - Shell, Helen (Box 18)
        - Small Business Program (Box 18)
        - T General (Box 18)
        - U General (Box 18)
        - Universities-National Bureau Committee for Economic Research (Box 18)
        - V General (Box 19)
        - W General (Box 19)
        - Wayne State University, Citizens Advisory Committee (Box 19)
        - XYZ General (Box 19)
        - Yang, Ju-Mei (Box 19)
      - 1959-1960
        - A General (Box 19)
        - American Association of Collegiate Schools of Business (Box 19)
        - Ann Arbor Bank (Box 19)
        - Association Executives of Michigan (Box 19)
        - B General (Box 19)
        - C General (Box 19)
        - Chicago, Alumni Group (Box 19)
        - Chicago, University of (Box 19)
        - Citizens for Michigan (Box 19)
        - Committee for Economic Development, 6 folders (Box 19)
        - Community Colleges, Citizens Advisory Committee on (Box 19)
        - D General (Box 19)
        - E General (Box 19)
        - Economic Club of Detroit (Box 19)
        - F General (Box 19)
        - Ferris Institute, April 14, 1959 (Box 19)
        - Ford Foundation, 2 folders (Box 19)
        - G General (Box 19)
        - General Electric, Crotonville Conference, July 24-29, 1960 (Box 19)
        - H General (Box 19)
        - Hale, Clayton G (Box 19)
        - Harvard University (Box 19)
        - I General (Box 19)
        - J General (Box 19)
        - Joint Council on Economic Education (Box 19)
        - K General (Box 19)
        - L General (Box 19)
        - M General (Box 19)
        - Michigan, State of (Box 19)
        - Michigan Council on Economic Education (Box 19)
        - Michigan, Department of Economic Development, 3 folders (Box 19)
        - Michigan's Economic Future, Committee on (Box 19)
        - Michigan, Governor's Task Force on Industrial Development, 2 folders (Box 19)
        - Michigan State University (Box 19)
        - Minnesota, University of (Box 19)
        - N General (Box 19)
        - Nakajima, Seigo (Box 19)
        - O General (Box 19)
        - P General (Box 19)
        - Paton, William A., Fund (Box 19)
        - Q-R General (Box 19)
        - S General (Box 19)
        - Stevenson Trip, Fall 1960 (Box 19)
        - T General (Box 19)
        - U-V General (Box 19)
        - W General (Box 19)
        - Wayne State University (Box 19)
  - Supplemental Administrative Records, 1924-1960
    Supplemental Administrative Records are largely documents generated by individuals other than the dean or his immediate staff that found their way into the dean's office, either by way of reference or for safekeeping. The Supplemental Administrative Records are divided into two subseries, Programs for Full-Time Students and Faculty and Programs for Special Groups. Programs for Full-Time Students and Faculty, 1924-60, details information about activities designed as part of the school's specific functions as an institution for higher learning. Primarily this means activities related to the school's degree granting activities, although information regarding the administration of the bureaus is also filed here. Prominently mentioned are the Business Research Bureau, Courses, the Curriculum Committee, the Executive Committee, the Hospital Administration Program, and the Bureau of Industrial Relations.
    Programs for Special Groups documents the many special presentations the school organized. The GSBA has maintained a strong tradition of serving private groups by organizing special lectures, seminars, short courses and other activities not intended to lead toward any degree but rather designed to update practitioners in a particular area of business with current academic research. Dating from 1932 to 1960, and arranged chronologically, Programs for Special Groups' records particularly document areas such as the annual alumni conference, real estate, accounting, public utilities administration, and bank management.
    - Programs for Full-Time Students and Faculty, 1924-1960